I analyzed these closed GraphQL
reports to see what works in real life.
And it's incredible what a
variety of bugs I've seen.
Because I have to admit, before I
mostly just tested authorization,
so this was very valuable for me,
and hopefully for you as well.
Enjoy!
In this video we'll go through
The types of bugs to which GraphQL
led and the most common one, of
course, it was authorization.
And I also have it split into
three different groups, read,
create, update, and delete.
And we'll start with the readbacks.
And this was by far the biggest group
of them all, with as much as 59 reports.
Some of them were pretty simple like
this one where you have the query that
fetches some objects in this type, it's
some media from Instagram, and you don't
even change the parameter to another
user is not like the typical query.
either where you change the ID and you get
the data of another user here, you just
added the email attribute to the request.
So along these medias, whatever it was,
you would also get emails of users.
And this is definitely valuable
information, impactful information that
Instagram does not want to have leaked.
But the majority of reports were pretty
simple ideas like this one and I feel
like I've seen the same report like
five or six time copy pasted report on
HackerOne because they had very similar
issues just in different queries.
You just have some query, you change
the idea, or in this case, the handle,
and you just get the data of something
you shouldn't be able to access.
And here, this was 2, 500 bounty.
There were a lot of reports
that were exactly like this one
with exactly the same bounty.
Then there were some that were
a little bit less impactful.
So the bounty was a bit less, but
the reports were very, similar.
So this is the most typical
GraphQL bug you will ever see.
With this, we'll jump to the
second biggest group, the create
or update mutations, and we
had very interesting bugs here.
The most impactful one, I would say was
this one from Watson group by J. Franz
Sibbitt, whatever, you should read this.
and I understand from the summary
because the report itself is not visible.
I understand from the summary, the
GraphQL was not supposed to be public.
So the first step, which is
not visible from, this part is
the discovery of the endpoint.
Maybe it was, under the different
path, maybe on some hidden subdomain.
But Then the user could register
on some website, and then as a
registered user, they could also
have the create admin user mutation.
So they will go from being
unauthenticated to being authenticated,
but with low privileges, to
being authenticated as the admin.
So it was reported, it was
rewarded as a critical.
And I would say it was probably one of
the most impactful bugs of the case study.
Then.
to complete the four operations you can
do with the data because you can read
create or update but you can also delete
which is always i'm saying you should also
test for this because it's less natural
to test for deletion it's a little bit
harder to test for deletion so bugs here
will definitely happen and the one i have
here from gitlab it is very interesting
what happened here so It's not your
typical IDO where you just change the ID
and turns out you can't delete the object.
You shouldn't be able to delete.
It's the case where you have the
mutation that's called destroy snippet.
I don't know what snippet is exactly in
GitLab, but we all understand what it is.
And the title of report is, you
can't delete the repository.
So how come?
you can delete the repository
using the delete snippet mutation.
And the answer is, the hunter
used the identifier like this.
So they use the destroy snippet
mutation, but then they used this
identifier, which, and we have the
sort of source code analysis here,
which caused this argument to not be
a snippet by, but a diff note object.
And apparently the code that was there
happens to just delete the repository
when this happened, which does not make
sense at all to me, even by looking at
the snippets, which seem understandable,
it's hard to accept how this could
happen, but it's very, interesting.
And the good information
is this type of identifier.
This is not something GitLab specific.
I've seen the same form
of Git in HackerOne.
I've seen the same in Meta.
So this is not something
created by GitLab.
It is more widely used.
So if you're testing the something
that's that uses GraphQL, you can
try to do this to confuse what object
are you trying to modify or delete.
This video is based on the
free part of the case study.
If you're enjoying it, you'll surely also
like the full article, where there are
crazy bugs like the either that's only
exploitable for 3 seconds, secondary
path traversals, race conditions,
cache related issues, and more.
crazy, things.
And also you will get access to the
whole database with all the reports,
as well as the other 12 case studies.
If you want to access them, go
to study at bug bounty explained.
com.
Next we'll go to denial of service bugs.
And we had a few reports here,
but only one of them is from, bug
bounty that was actually rewarded.
The other are zero days.
And if you've watched this presentation
by Ronnie about practical exploitation
of denial of service in bug bounty, you
know that GraphQL has big, potential to
be vulnerable to denial of service bugs.
And I can also confirm this from my
experience that it is quite easy to find.
The bigger problem is if you can get
reward for it, cause as those bugs
go, they And they are a bit random
whether the program will reward them
or not, so it's always a bit of a
mystery when you're reporting the bug.
Here they got the bounty of actually
the base bounty was just 1, 000,
but then they got the bonus for the
coolest bug of the whole event because
this was the google event So they
got another 5, 000 on top of this.
So it was a really nice bug.
They Batched the directives which were
used in a little bit of an unnatural
way for them So it was very creative
and very nice and nice for google
to reward it as well Then as the
next group, we have SQL injection.
And this one, you can, of course,
expect some, to some extent, the SQL
injection in the parameter, because
GraphQL itself, it is not a database.
It is not actually something
that stores your data.
What it does is it takes your HTTP
request with the GraphQL query in it,
And it translates to something that the
developers implement on the backend.
So it might be the HTTP request
to some backend service.
It can just be something that from you
to the server, you send the GraphQL
query and the server makes different
REST API requests on the backend,
because it's much quicker for the
server than it would be for you to
send, let's say, 10 REST API requests.
Another case, maybe SQL query, where.
The GraphQL query is transformed to SQL
query and the data is then returned.
So normal SQL injection
is somewhat expected.
But the one that was here in
HackerOne was really, interesting.
Because it actually did not
happen inside of the query.
it's something that before
the query is executed, sets
some session keys and values.
And apparently it was used internally
without user input ever getting to here.
So there was no problem with this.
But then there was some other
code, which I don't think is
mentioned here, that caused the URL
parameter to land in this session.
So here you can see the request.
And you can see there is not even
a GraphQL query in this request.
There is just the request
to the GraphQL endpoint.
And you have the query parameter with
the fairly typical Postgres SQL injection
payload with the sleep comment, and you
can see the times here to confirm it.
So a very, interesting bug.
I didn't know we've without
access to the source code.
someone would thing that you
should also test for SQL injection
in the parameters of the request
itself, not the GraphQL parameters.
So it's very interesting and
very, cool bug with, big impact.
Of course, this was not rewarded because
it's, it was found internally by the
HackerOne team, but they still submitted
this HackerOne reports and this,
they, give report the real severity.
And this was a 10 out of 10 critical.
Understandably.
Then we'll go to the next group,
which is not something that I like.
And if you're a long time viewer of
the channel, you probably know this
because there were three reports
that I found that were Nothing more
but reporting just the fact that the
GraphQL schema was disclosed, which by
itself is not a vulnerability, it can
allow vulnerabilities to happen, and
it can make the exploitation easier.
But by itself, I don't think
there's any security impact.
But some people did report it.
And this report that I have here,
It even got the bounty of, I
think he said between six and 800.
So you can probably try to do
it, but I would not advise it.
If you have so much data, try to find
what queries and mutations you can use
or do what we did or the hundred it
in the beginning of the video, where.
You have the usual query, which is
something you have access to it.
It's not a violation of any access
control, but you just add some
attribute to it that all of a sudden
leaks the sensitive data back to you.
This is what I think you should
try if you have the introspection.
And finally, we have one last
group, the CSRF, and I very much
liked the finding that was here.
It is actually And not the
bug bounty, it is the security
auditing report by Doyensec.
And they found the CSRF
using the head method.
And if you remember a few years
ago, there was the OCSRF in GitHub
that used exactly the same method.
So there was code like this, which sort of
explicitly checked if the method is get.
And then there was some things that
were happening if the method was get,
were not state changing because the
get is not subject to CSRF protection.
So it cannot change or modify any data.
So in context of GraphQL speaking
directly, it should, get should
only be allowed to do GraphQL
queries and not GraphQL mutations.
But here there was the explicit
check for the get method.
And the thing is, automatically
the router would send head requests
to the same sort of piece of code.
So heads would implicitly land
in the same function as gets.
But then when it comes to the
check like this, head is no longer
treated the same way as the get is.
So head would Not have the CSR protection
and then not get to this non state
changing part of the source code.
So it would land in the
same place as post would.
And you could easily just have
the query in the URL parameter.
So a very, nice report.
I really like the one in
GitHub a few years ago.
And I really like this one as well.
And this is everything when it comes
to, the back classes in GraphQL.
Again, appreciate you
sticking around to the end.
If you want to deepen your knowledge even
more about GraphQL, check out the full
article, check out the report database.
And if you prefer just sticking to
the free stuff, check out the playlist
that's on your screen right now.
For now, thank you so much
for watching and goodbye.